<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Bárbara</title>
    <link>/</link>
      <atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Bárbara</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 27 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>/images/icon_hu0b7a4cb9992c9ac0e91bd28ffd38dd00_9727_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_2.png</url>
      <title>Bárbara</title>
      <link>/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Towards Safe Human-Quadrotor Interaction: Mixed-Initiative Control via Real-Time NMPC</title>
      <link>/publication/micontroller_ral/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/publication/micontroller_ral/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>An Efficient Real-Time NMPC for Quadrotor Position Control under Communication Time-Delay</title>
      <link>/publication/crazyflie_icarcv/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 12 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/publication/crazyflie_icarcv/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Least Conservative Linearized Constraint Formulation for Real-Time Motion Generation</title>
      <link>/publication/crazyflie_ifac/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/publication/crazyflie_ifac/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Enforcing Constraints over Learned Policies via Nonlinear MPC: Application to the Pendubot</title>
      <link>/publication/pendubot_ifac/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/publication/pendubot_ifac/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>MikroKopter</title>
      <link>/project/mikrokopter/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/project/mikrokopter/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p align=&#34;justify&#34;&gt; During my time as a visiting PhD student at the LAAS-CNRS, Toulouse, France, I worked intensively with the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.mikrokopter.de/en/home&#34;&gt;MikroKopter&lt;/a&gt; platform. I was under the supervision of Dr. Antonio Franchi at the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.laas.fr/public/en/ris&#34;&gt;Robotics and Interactions (RIS) team&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p align=&#34;justify&#34;&gt; As the platform was equipped with an &lt;a href=&#34;https://ark.intel.com/content/www/us/en/ark/products/95068/intel-nuc-board-nuc7i7bnb.html&#34;&gt;Intel NUC7i7BNB&lt;/a&gt;, I developed a tailored NMPC, able to take advantage of the computational resources of the target CPU and run efficiently onboard. All subsequent solutions were then able to benefit from this base framework, developed under the GenoM3 architecture. One of those solutions was an NMPC applied to a quadrotor-slung payload system for the task of transportation on suspension. Another solution was a mixed-initiative control method for human-quadrotor interaction based on real-time NMPC. This method handles the complex connection between the human inputs and the automatic controller commands for cooperative tasks. It was numerically validated using the dynamic model of the actual MikroKopter.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Crazyflie</title>
      <link>/project/crazyflie/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/project/crazyflie/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p align=&#34;justify&#34;&gt; During my time as a visiting PhD student at IMTEK University of Freiburg, Germany, I used the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.bitcraze.io/crazyflie-2-1/&#34;&gt;Crazyflie 2.1&lt;/a&gt; nanoquadrotor as the platform for my projects. I was under the supervision of professor Moritz Diehl at the Systems Control and Optimization Laboratory (syscop), supported by the &lt;a href=&#34;http://ais.informatik.uni-freiburg.de/index_en.php&#34;&gt;Autonomous Intelligent Systems Lab (AIS)&lt;/a&gt; of professor Wolfram Burgard and also &lt;a href=&#34;https://kiteswarms.com&#34;&gt;Kiteswarms&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p align=&#34;justify&#34;&gt; When flying, Crazyflie can send a limited amount of data back to the ground station. Depending on the size of the data package, the latency inherent in receiving the request may be so significant as to degrade the performance during flight. Due to this effect, most control strategies are designed to run onboard, where this shortcoming is mitigated, and fast angular position and rate stabilization is achieved. However, the limited computational resources onboard also limit the range of control techniques that can be used for stabilization. Taking these problems and limitations into account, I initially proposed a time-delay compensation strategy so that an offboard NMPC could be used for position control. Later, I proposed a scheme for real-time motion generation in dynamic environments, built on top of the previous solution.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pendubot</title>
      <link>/project/pendubot/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/project/pendubot/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p align=&#34;justify&#34;&gt; This was my first project working with real-time NMPC. Here, the NMPC was combined with a learned control policy to enforce safety in robotic systems. The algorithm was validated using the Pendubot, a challenging underactuated system, in a swing-up task.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Autopilot</title>
      <link>/project/autopilot/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/project/autopilot/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p align=&#34;justify&#34;&gt;My undergraduate research focused essentially on developing a flight controller for a quadcopter prototype. I used a &lt;a href=&#34;https://beagleboard.org/black&#34;&gt;Beaglebone Black (BBB) Rev C&lt;/a&gt; with Debian 8 Jessie as a development board. The software had three layers, divided as follows: &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt; Low level: sonar altitude measurements. This layer was written in Assembly and designed for the BBB&#39;s programmable real-time unit (PRU).&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt; Middle level: motor PWM signals. This layer was written in C and compiled as shared libraries.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt; High level: calibration and reading of sensors, control law, and motor output. This layer was written in Python.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p align=&#34;justify&#34;&gt; I also contributed to the development of a BBB Device Tree Source, as I needed a custom management of the board&#39;s I/O pins in my project. The source files can be found &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/beagleboard/devicetree-source&#34; class=&#34;link link--dark&#34;&gt;here.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
